-==http://www.1000fr.com== 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
www.1000fr.com presents
福尔摩斯探案 之回忆录
The memoris of Sherlock Homels
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
第七季 第一集
S7E01
你答应了的
You promised.
我什么也没有答应过你
I promised you nothing.
跟我走吧
?
绝不
Never.
我要去罗马了
I'm leaving for Rome.
请你...请你跟我一起走
Please, please come with me.
我已经放手了
I've given up.
我再没有什么可以给你的了
I have no more to give.
为什么 为什么你要这么对待我?
Why, why do you treat me like this?
不
No.
走啊 走  给我走
Go, go, go, go.
无情 卑鄙
Heartless, mean.
就在那一刻 爱情死去了
It was at that moment that love died
憎恨萌生了
and hate was born.
三角墙山庄
The Three Gables
Violet
Violet.
你好 华生
Hi, Watson.
你来得正好
Well timed.
跟Steve Dixie握个手吧 他是位拳击手
Shake hands with Steve Dixie, the pugilist
他在这一行可是前途无量啊
for why to have a future in this profession
如果不结交损友的话
if you didn't mix with bad company.
这儿到底发生了什么事?
What is happening here?
哎 让他少管闲事
Abe, meddling in affairs that don't concern him.
我警告了他 可是他目中无人
Now I warned him and he got cocky.
不不 说吧说吧 没事儿
No, keep talking, keep talking it's fine.
没关系 是吧?
It's fine is it?
哼 要是我狠狠地揍你一顿
Well, it won't be so damn fine
还会没事儿吗?
if I have to thump you around a bit.
别动手 华生 别动手
Stop it, Watson, stop it.
我们听听 是谁派他来滋事生非的
Let us hear who has sent him on this belligerent errand.
坐下 Dixie
Sit down Dixie.
跟我谈谈吧
Talk to me.
哈 谢谢
Ah, thank you,
现在告诉我是怎么回事
now tell me what this is all about.
我什么也不会说的 福尔摩斯先生
I ain't telling you nothing, Mr. Holmes,
我只想告诉你离Harrow远点
except you keep away from Harrow.
我这几个月都没去过Harrow
I haven't been in Harrow in months.
你知道我在说什么
You know what I'm talking about.
我警告你
I'm warning you,
离得远点
keep away.
关于在Holburn酒吧外
On the matter of the killing of Perkins
Perkins被杀一事...
outside the Holburn Bar.
跟我一点关系也没有
I had nothing to do with that.
那男孩被杀的时候
I was training, yeah,
我正在伯明翰的斗牛场上 进行着训练
at the bullring in Birmingham when that boy got done.
这个你跟治安官说去 Hudson太太
You'll tell that to the magistrate, Mrs. Hudson.
瞧 不要太激动嘛 对吧 福尔摩斯先生
Look, no hard feelings, aye, Mr. Holmes?
Hudson太太 这里有点小骚乱
Mrs. Hudson, there's been a slight disturbance.
噢 我只是听命于人
Oh, yeah, I just done what I was told.
替我问候Barney Stockdale
My regards to Barney Stockdale.
就是你把这儿搞得一团糟的吗
Are you responsible for this mess.
马上给我下去 下楼去
Go on down those stairs with you at once.
噢 他真是个温顺的家伙
Oh, he's a harmless enough fellow
胆子又小 你都看到了
and easily coward as you see.
他是Spencer John团伙里的一个
One of the Spencer John gang,
专搞袭击恐吓之类的事情
assaults, intimidation and the like.
他们干嘛要恐吓你?
Why would they want to intimidate you?
谁是Barney Stockdale?
And who's Barney Stockdale?
他是他的上级主使
He's immediate principal.
又是谁付钱给Barney Stockdale呢?
Who's paying Barney Stockdale I wonder?
Harrow Weald的三角墙山庄
The Three Gables Harrow Weald.
他打烂了我们的窗户
He's broken our window.
亲爱的歇洛克.福尔摩斯先生
Dear Mr. Sherlock Holmes,
我这里发生了一连串 跟我的屋子有关的怪事
I've had a succession of strange incidents occur to me in connection with my house.
我想听听您的意见
And I should much value your advice.
明天随时欢迎您光临寒舍
You would find me at home any time tomorrow.
我已故的丈夫Mortimer Maberley
I believe that my late husband Mortimer Maberley
曾是您早期的主顾之一
was one of your early client.
您忠诚的
Yours faithfully,
Mary Maberley
Mary Maberley.
Steve Dixie带来的这个有趣插曲
This comic interlude with Steve Dixie
让我相信这里头一定有古怪
convinces me there must be something in it.
我们发电报给她 然后马上动身吧
Let us wire her and go out there at once.
您丈夫跟我相当熟悉 夫人
I knew your husband well, Madame,
不过那是很多年前的事情了
but it was some years ago.
嗯 我的丈夫
Well, it's some years
他去世也有些年头了
since he's been with us the dear man.
要不要尝点这个?
Oh, will you try some of this?
我自己烤的
I baked it myself.
那位是Douglas Maberley吗
That's Douglas Maberley.
是的
Yes.
我跟他有些浅交
I knew him slightly.
他很出色
He's a splendid fellow.
他在我以前的Black Heath俱乐部打橄榄球
He plays rugby for my old club Black Heath.
-我是他的奶奶 -哦
-I'm his grandmother. -Oh.
我曾经是他的奶奶
I was his grandmother.
他一个月前去世了
He died a month ago.
去世了?
Died?
你没听说吗?
You hadn't heard?
是的 让人伤心的结局
No, it was a sad ending.
噢 真遗憾
Oh, I'm so sorry,
他看上去是那么充满活力
he seemed so full of life and energy
很难把他和死亡联系在一起
it's hard to connect.
他的感情过于丰富了
He lived too intensely.
这一点把他毁了
It was the ruin of him.
是一起意外吧?
Was it an accident?
我上次还听说
I mean the last I heard
他被派往罗马的使馆工作呢
he'd been appointed attach?to our embassy in Rome.
他就在这房子里头死的
He died in this house,
他们说是肺炎
of pneumonia they say
是由脾脏破裂引起的
brought on by a ruptured spleen
不过我今天请你们来
but it's not to talk of my grandson
不是要来谈我孙子的
that I asked you here.
我们都来了
Well, we are here, please.
是来为您效劳的
To give you service.
谢谢
Thank you.
我在这房子里住了有一年多
Well I've been in this house for over a year now
过着隐居的生活
leading a retired life.
三天前我接到一个房产经纪的电话
Three days ago I had a call from a house agent.
钱不是问题 夫人
The money is no object, Madame.
可是附近有好几间待售的屋子呢
But there's several empty houses around here on the market.
不 就要这间 我的委托人对这间屋子情有独钟
No, this, my client's heart is set on this one.
你开个价好吗?
Will you name your price?
我开的价比买进价高了500英镑
I suggested 500 pounds more than I gave for it.
他说他的委托人...
He said that his client...
我的委托人还想连家具一起买
My client desires to buy the furniture as well.
全部家具吗?
All of it?
是的
Everything.
有些家具可是上等质地的啊
But some of it's very good.
尽管开价就行 Maberley太太
Just state your price, Mrs. Maberley.
于是我就开了个高价 他马上就答应了
So I did, a good round sum and he agreed at once.
我一直希望有可能的话能去周游世界
You see I've always wanted to travel around the world if I could.
这也是我先生的遗愿
It's a legacy left to me by my dear Mortimer.
我们从未实现过
No less, we never really achieved it.
那人第二天回来时 是不是把协议都起草好了?
The man returned the next day with everything drawn up?
就是昨天的事 幸好我把协议 给我的律师Sutro先生看了
Yesterday, luckily I showed it to Mr. Sutro, my lawyer.
真是怪事
This is very strange.
你有没有注意到 协议不许你带走房子里的任何东西
Are you aware that you cannot take anything out of the house
甚至是你个人的财产也不行?
not even your own personal possessions?
我的衣服也不行吗?
Not my clothes,
还有我的珠宝?
my jewelry?
什么都不行
Anything.
那个人再来的时候
When the man returned to the house
您有没有向他指出这一点?
you pointed this out?
有的
Yes.
他说我可以带走一些个人的东西
He said I might take some personal effects
但是要带走的东西 一律得经过检查
but that nothing should go out of this house unchecked.
我的委托人很慷慨
My client is very liberal
但有些怪癖 夫人
but has fads, Madame,
做事情有他自己的方式
and a way of doing things.
你的东西嘛 我的委托人要么就全要
I'm afraid it must be everything
要么就全部都不要
or nothing for my client.
那就全都不要好了
Then it must be nothing.
这就是他的名片
Here it is.
Haines Johnson 拍卖估价师 没有留下地址
Haines Johnson, auctioneer valuer no address.
我怀疑我们能否在号码本里找到他
I doubt we shall find him in the directory,
诚实的人不会隐瞒自己的地址的
honest men don't conceal their place of business.
对于偷听的来说 你的喘息声太大了
Just a little wheezy for eavesdropping.
我只不过想进来问问
I just came in to find out
客人们是否会留下来用午餐 夫人
if the visitors were staying for lunch, Madame.
别逼我用这个
Don't force me to use this.
Maberley太太
Mrs. Maberley, did you mention to anyone
您有没有跟别人说起过要向我咨询的事?
that you were going to consult me?
没有 福尔摩斯先生
I did not, Mr. Holmes.
信是谁寄的?
Who posted the letter?
Susan
Susan did.
Susan?
哈 你把消息透露给谁了?
Ah, to whom did you send your message?
我没有向别人透露什么消息
I sent no message.
告诉我
Tell me?
Susan 我记起来了
Susan, I remember now,
我看见你在篱笆那里跟人说话来着
I saw you speaking to someone over the hedge.
那是我的私事 夫人
That was my own business, Madame.
是Barney Stockdale
Barney Stockdale.
怎么可能
Fine chance that would be.
我都不认识他
I didn't even know the man.
要是你告诉我 这事是谁在背后搞的鬼
It is worth 10 pounds to you
我给你10英镑
if you tell me who is at the back of this.
你的10英镑的消息
Someone who could lay down 1,000 pounds
有人可愿意花上1000镑呢
for every 10 you've got in the world.
我看见一个有钱人在微笑
I see a rich man who smiled,
是一个有钱的女人
a rich woman.
把名字告诉我 你就可以把钱拿去
Tell me the name and earn the money.
我要先看到你下地狱
I'll see you in hell first.
明天我派人来取我的箱子 夫人
I'll send for my box tomorrow, Madame.
这群团伙出现意味着有猫腻
This gang means business.
可是他们想要什么呢?
But what can they possibly want?
Maberley太太
Mrs. Maberley,
您说您在这房子里住了有一年了?
you say you've been in this house for a year?
差不多两年
Nearly two.
这么说 近两年来
So for nearly two years
没人对这房子 有什么特别的兴趣
no one has taken any particular interest in the house
然而就在三四天前 突然就有人这么急需
and yet suddenly within three or four days
这房子和里头的东西
urgent demands are made for it and its contents.
房子里肯定添置了什么新的东西
Something new must've been brought into the house.
没有 我有一年多没买什么新东西了
No, I haven't bought anything new for a year.
这个Susan来这儿多久了?
This, Susan, how long has she been with you?
大概三个星期
Almost three weeks.
就在你孙子死后吗?
Since your grandson's death?
他去世一星期后的事
A week after.
她向我自荐
She presented herself
而我就雇佣了她
and I took her in I suppose
呃 也没有什么介绍信
without proper reference.
这蛋糕很好吃
You know, this cake is delicious.
能说说 您孙子从意大利回来的情形吗?
Please, now will you tell us about the circumstances of your grandson's return to Italy?
我那多情的孩子
My gallant boy.
你也许还记得 他曾是一个 多么快活 优秀的人吧 华生医生
You may remember him as debonair and splendid, Dr. Watson.
你都没有看到
You didn't see the morose
他变得多么郁郁寡欢心事重重
and brooding creature he became.
他的心都碎了
His heart was broken.
一月之间
In a single month
我看着他变成了一个衰弱又愤世嫉俗的人
I watched him turn into a worn out cynical man.
女人吗?
A woman?
他不肯说
He wouldn't speak of it.
他说他怕让他的奶奶也跟着烦恼
He was afraid of upsetting his grandma he said.
那您一直都不知道她的名字了?
And so you never learnt her name?
今晚最好能有人
It might be advisable
跟您呆在一起
for someone to stay with you tonight.
华生?
Watson?
好的 没问题
Yes, of course.
不 我真的不能麻烦你
No, I really couldn't ask such a thing.
不不不 我们要走了
No, no, no, we're leaving.
谢谢 Maberley太太
Thank you, Mrs. Maberley,
我天黑前回来
I shall be back before dark,
您别担心
don't concern yourself.
也许要找到这个人才行
It might be useful to find this
她叫什么?  Violet吗?
what's she called, Violet.
他也许向她透露了什么事情
He may have confided something to her
他到死也没有
that he didn't tell his grandmother
跟他奶奶说起的事情
in his last hours.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
下午好 Dixie先生
Good Afternoon Mr. Dixie.
那老太太和她的房子
The old lady and the house
都在我的保护之下
are both under my protection
你可别忘了
and don't you forget it.
看看他们是不是走了
Make sure they're gone.
今晚带上你的手枪
Bring your revolver tonight.
D代表Douglas Maberley
D, Douglas Maberley,
出色 快活
splendid, debonair,
同时又阴郁 愤世嫉俗
too morose, cynical,
好重的词
strong words.
噢 不
Oh, no,
这个没有眼睛的女士是谁?
who is this lady with no eyes?
我们去那边查
Our course lies there.
应该是样连她自己都不知道 已经在手上的东西
There must be something she doesn't know she has.
就算她知道 也许也不肯告诉我们
And probably wouldn't tell us even if she did know.
这案子要找Langdale Pike
This is a case for Langdale Pike.
那个卑鄙的无赖
That reptile.
胡说
Nonsense, don't talk rubbish.
他是个爱讲闲话的人
He's a gossip,
但是...也许他能指认出那个贵妇人
but he might identify this rich woman.
真是令人难过 他在大学的时候可是很出色的
Sad, he was brilliant at university,
我总觉得 在他外表之下
and you know, I've always felt that under that veneer
藏着一颗孤独的心
that he was totally isolated.
就像我
Like me.
你看到了吗?
You see that?
那边在树下的女孩
That young girl there, under the tree,
戴着一顶应景的帽子
with the occasional hat,
你觉得她在干嘛?
what do you make of her?
她在找她的狗
She's looking for her dog.
什么?
What?
-不 当然不是 -一条萨卢基狗
-No, no, surely. -A saluki,
也许戴着松绿色的项圈
with a turquoise collar perhaps.
她对这公园很陌生
She's a stranger in the park
她的狗也是
so is the dog.
它来了
There it is now.
你怎么知道的?
How did you know that?
她的靴子是乡村款式的
Her boots are country boots
但已经不够结实
but not so robust,
说明她来自崎岖的丘陵地区
as to suggest a rough terrain.
Wiltshire来的
Wiltshire,
也许是来自Gloucestershire
Gloucestershire perhaps.
是的 是的 但是...
Yes, yes, yes, but,
你有没有发现她很迷人?
don't you find her attractive?
好吧
All right.
为什么是一条萨卢基狗?
Why saluki?
人们常说"狗似主人形"
Owners are meant to look like their dogs, they say,
难道不就是萨卢基了吗?
wouldn't you say, saluki?
厉害
Remarkable.
事实上
She is in point of fact,
她是Geraldine Windridge小姐
Lady Geraldine Windridge
来自Wiltshire的Marlborough家的近亲
the close Marlborough, Wiltshire.
现在说说 亲爱的福尔摩斯 你找我干嘛来了?
And now my, dear Holmes, what is it you want from me?
是关于已故的Douglas Maberley
The late Douglas Maberley.
可怜的孩子
Poor boy,
真是可惜了
and what a waste.
他与一位女士有染
He was involved with a lady
一位贵妇人
a well placed rich lady.
你知道吗?
Known to you?
你有什么可以交换的吗
Have you something to trade,
有来有往?
tittle for tattle?
Langdale 我很急的
Langdale, I'm in a hurry.
嗯 谢谢
Hmm, thank you.
她名叫Isadora Klein
Her name is Isadora Klein.
啊 没错 是德国糖业大王的遗孀
Ah, yes, widow of the German sugar king,
相当出名的一位美人儿
quite a celebrated beauty.
著名的美人儿
The celebrated beauty.
她和年轻的Lomond公爵订了婚
She's engaged to be married
就要结婚了
to the youthful Duke of Lomond.
Pike还告诉你什么了
What else did Pike tell you,
有没有告诉你她和Maberley的事?
anything about her and Maberley?
没有
Nothing.
福尔摩斯
I wonder, Holmes,
你觉得有没有可能 她想拿回一些有损声名的信件?
do you think it could be about some compromising letters she wants retrieved,
特别是会影响她即将举行的婚礼的信件
I mean particularly in view of her forthcoming marriage.
你是说情信吗?
You mean love letters?
不 不 应该不止这样
No, no, it's deeper than that.
听着 我要你
Listen, I demand that you spend
在三角墙山庄
a sleepless night
彻夜守候
at the Three Gables
枪不离手
with that revolver at hand.
你今晚怎么过?
How will you be spending the evening?
从另一个角度追踪这个案件
Pursuing the matter from another angle,
去查一下当事人
examining the principal.
你有什么要告诉我的 Miguel?
So, what is it you have to tell me, Miguel?
那个愚蠢的Susan已经 离开Maberley家的房子了
That stupid woman Susan has left the Maberley house.
离开?
Left?
她声称是被歇洛克.福尔摩斯先生撵走的
Was forced to leave she claims by Mr. Sherlock Holmes.
他无视我们要他远离Harrow的要求
He's refused our request to avoid Harrow.
歇洛克.福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes,
那是因为你的要求不够强硬
then you did not request him hard enough.
那么
Well,
歇洛克.福尔摩斯先生在调查这个案子了
so Mr. Sherlock Holmes is on the case.
他拜访了那位老妇人
He paid a visit to the old lady
不过空手而返
but left empty handed.
不用担心
Have no fear.
我们时间不多了 Miguel
We're losing time, Miguel,
今晚就得动手
we must act tonight,
你安排一下
arrange it.
这位福尔摩斯先生倒是引起了我的兴趣
This Mr. Sherlock Holmes intrigues me.
他聪明吗?
Is he clever?
他可是声名在外
He has a reputation.
侦破疑案很出名 没错
For solving crimes, yes,
可是对付女人呢?
but for women?
你还欠我一个人情 伙计 你记得吗?
You still owe me a favor dear boy, remember?
你要是不还我人情
I shan't destroy the paper
那张纸我可不撕掉
until you've returned the compliment,
还记得吧 有来有往?
remember tittle for tattle?
看看你 到底怎么啦?
Look at you, I mean what's all this?
啊 当然了
Oh, of course,
我们现在参加的是中产阶级的化妆晚会
we are above the bourgeois epitan costume,
狂欢已经开始了
the revels have begun.
就算没有你那朦胧的谜题 生活也已经够神秘了
Life is mystery enough without your pale conundrums.
噢 这么多人
Oh, so many people,
却如此没有目标
so little purpose.
那是上帝的谜题
That's God's conundrum.
要是我们这样的凡夫俗子能回答就好了
If only we mortals could answer that.
那你的生活也没什么意思了
Then your life would have no meaning.
真实却又残酷  残酷但很真实
True, cruel, cruel but so true.
我总是说我们已故的朋友
I've always said that if our late mutual friend,
Charles Augustus Milverton是个坏天使
Charles Augustus Milverton was the bad angel.
而我可是个好天使
I am the good angel.
我秘而不宣的事比我透露的可是多得多
I suppress much, much more than I expose,
否则 这世界会怎样呢?
what sort of world would it be if I didn't?
她是哪一位?
Which one is she?
在那边 亲爱的
Over there my dear fellow,
你不会认错她的 跟年轻的Lomond在一起
you could hardly mistake her, with young Lomond.
"无情的美妇人" (济慈的一首诗)
La belle dame sans merci.
Douglas Maberley
Douglas Maberley.
还有其他人
And others.
其他 其他 还有其他
All those, all those and then those.
Douglas是伦敦 最为引人注目的年轻人之一
Douglas was one of the most striking young men in London.
他倾尽所有
He gave all,
也希望得到一切
and expected all.
是她结束了这段关系
It was she who ended it.
残忍地
Brutally.
嫁给一位出身平凡 不名一文的外交官
Married to the penniless diplomat of little breeding
可不在这寡妇的计划之中
was not in the widow's plans.
你没读过我的专栏吗?
Don't your read my column?
然而他好像
And yet he seems,
死后还握着她的什么把柄
even in death to have some hold over her,
是什么呢?
what is it?
我给你提供的资料 你想怎么用都行
Do what you like with the information I gave you
不过不要跟她做交易
but have no truck with her.
瞧 看见她都让我毛发直竖
Look, the sight of her set my hairs on end.
她是致命的
She's deadly.
而现在
And now she has
伟大的公爵都被她操控于股掌之中
her great Duke aligned within her grasp.
看看他们
Look at them.
她都老得可以当他的...
She's old enough to be his...
啊 那苦恼的母亲
ah, the anguished mother.
我曾经帮过她丈夫
I helped her husband once.
你现在找她干嘛呢?
What is your interest in her now?
Douglas已经作古了
Douglas is history,
他已经归于尘土了
he's dust, dust.
我们不都这样吗?
Aren't we all,
不都这样吗?
aren't we all.
连你也一样
Even you.
我可不是 伙计 我可不是
Not me dear boy, not me.
我可是能经受住时间的风霜的
I withstand the blasts of time.
你没发现吗?
Can't you see?
晚上好
Good evening.
当时我正要动身去印度
I was on my way to India,
当一户人家的家庭女教师
governess to a family
刚好就碰到了我亲爱的Mortimer
when I met my dear Mortimer.
他走的是另一条路线
He was going the other way.
这是他当时戴的帽子
This is the hat he was wearing,
60多年前了
over 60 years ago.
可您从没到过印度吧?
But you never got to India?
是的 我回头跟他一起走了
No, I turned back and went with him.
噢 当时好多人反对
Oh, the fuss.
那时他是个身无分文的推销员
You see he was a penniless salesman at the time,
卖整肠药水的 就是治婴儿肚痛的
gripe water, you know, the things in baby's tummies.
可是他骨子里是个爱冒险的人
But in his heart and soul was adventure.
我们计划去周游全世界
The places we planned to visit all over the world,
可是我们从没有离开过Harrow
We never left Harrow.
这照片上是Mortimer和Douglas吗?
Is that, is this Mortimer with Douglas?
噢 天哪
Oh, good heavens,
我竟还保存着它 真是太好了
have I kept that, how wonderful.
他们彼此深爱对方
They doted on each other.
他俩在很多方面都很相似
They were alike in so many ways,
一个模子印出来的
two peas in a pod.
他的父母亲怎么了?
And what happened to his mother and father?
我儿子和儿媳
Oh my son and his wife
造攀登Snowdonia峰的时候死于了意外
were killed in a climbing accident in Snowdonia
那时Douglas只有两岁
when Douglas was only two years old.
我们养大了他 把他当作自己的孩子
We brought him up as our own you see.
Harrow的案子?
This case in Harrow?
跟你未来的儿媳
It concerns your future daughter-in-law
跟她的一位已故的熟人有关
and a late acquaintance of hers.
事实对她不利
The facts do her no credit.
她过去的风流韵事?
Something from her past?
我就知道
I knew it.
请马上告诉我
Tell me at once.
我还需要点时间
I need a little time.
令我难过的婚礼很快就到了
The wedding, which I deplore, is almost upon us.
我那好孩子
My golden boy.
他被这女人迷得神魂颠倒
He's besotted with this woman.
要是你知道什么对她不利的事情
If you know something against her,
求你现在就揭晓吧
pray God let the scandal break now.
噢 不不不
Oh, no, no, no,
我想丑闻是可以避免的
I think a scandal can be avoided.
有什么我能做的吗?
Is there anything you wish me to do?
我需要的就是这次会面罢了
Granting me this interview was all that I needed.
Klein夫人在这儿见到我 可是不会高兴的
Mrs. Klein will not have been pleased to see me here.
Klein夫人
Mrs. Klein.
Harry在坟墓里都会不得安宁的
Harry would be turning in his grave.
都交给我来办吧
Leave all to me, please.
Maberley太太!
Mrs. Maberley!
快去
Leave me.
去追他们
Go after them.
他们得手了 走啊
They've got it, go.
噢 请快点 哦
Oh, please hurry, oh.
噢 快啊
Oh, hurry, please.
Steve Dixie
Steve Dixie.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes,
福尔摩斯先生 醒醒
Mr. Holmes, wake up.
大事不好了
It's bad news I'm afraid.
醒醒 福尔摩斯先生
Wake up, Mr. Holmes.
福尔摩斯先生?
Mr. Holmes?
-不好了 福尔摩斯先生 -什么?
-It's bad news, Mr. Holmes. -What?
医生他...
It's the doctor.
他在Harrow受到了严重的袭击
He's been brutally attacked in Harrow.
不 不 他还活着
No, no, he's alive.
他...或是律师发电报过来了
He wired or rather the lawyer did
说要是你不在的话 让我务必找到你
to say I was to find you if you weren't in
还要你尽快赶到那儿去
and you're to get there as soon as possible
我会给他做好吃的鲭鱼 给他当茶点
and I'd got him a nice piece of mackerel for his tea.
Dora 华生医生在哪儿?
Dora, where's Dr. Watson?
他在楼上 先生
He's upstairs, sir.
他怎么样了?
How is he?
我不知道 先生
I don't know, sir,
他早餐吃得不错
he had a good breakfast.
你家女主人呢?
Your mistress?
她在休息 先生
She's resting, sir.
她伤得不重 可是很受惊
She wasn't badly hurtbut she's had a nasty shock.
我们都是
We all have.
老天啊 你都碰上什么事了?
Good Lord, what have you got into?
发生了什么事?
What happened?
太太说你一到她就要见你
Madame says she wants to see you
福尔摩斯先生
as soon as you arrive, Mr. Holmes, sir.
福尔摩斯 她现在很虚弱
Holmes, she's in a very frail condition.
医生 先医好你自己再说吧
Physician, heal thyself.
福尔摩斯先生 你可真好
Mr. Holmes, how good of you.
您觉得怎么样?
How are you feeling?
呃 我还活着
Well, I'm alive
多亏了您勇敢的朋友 华生医生
thanks to your brave friend Dr. Watson.
他把它从他们手里夺回来了吗?
Did he get it back from them?
夺回什么?
Get what?
噢 对了 你还不知道 我没有...
Oh, of course you wouldn't know. I don't...
福尔摩斯先生 我得向您道歉
Mr. Holmes I owe you an apology.
我原先希望它跟这件事无关 可它真的有关
I prayed it would have no bearing but it does.
我真是太蠢了
Oh, it's so stupid of me.
它就是一切的根源
It's the reason for everything.
Douglas在写书
Douglas was writing a book.
他说书里会解释一切
He said it would explain it all.
他在罗马的时候开始提笔
He started it in Rome
后来他们把他送回这里后
and later when they brought him back here,
他就在那个通风的避暑亭里 坐上几个小时写东西
he sat for hours in that drafty little summer house,
甚至在十分糟糕的天气里
writing sometimes in the most dreadful weather.
后来他连床都起不来了
And later when he could no longer leave his room,
可他还是挣扎着写他的书
he still struggled with it.
有两本
Two copies,
一本他给了Violet
one he gave to Violet
要她把书寄给某个人
and told her to deliver it to someone.
我不知道是谁
I don't know who.
他要她发誓保密的
He had sworn her to secrecy,
而她也信守诺言
and she kept her promise.
另外一本
The other copy,
他催促我
he urged me,
几乎用尽他的最后一口气
almost with his dying breath
要我把它拿给他的出版商
to send it to his publisher.
我本来是要这么做的
I should've done so
不过就在他下葬的那一夜
but on the night of his funeral,
我太想念他了 于是就把整本书都看了
and missing him so much I read it through.
我马上就知道那本书是什么了 那是他的一生
I knew at once what it was, his life.
还有那个女人
That woman,
我甚至连她的名字都不知道
I didn't even know her name.
想到这本书会引发的丑闻
The scandal it would cause
我就把它埋在了心底
and I shut it out of my mind,
锁了起来
locked it away,
昨天晚上是华生医生让我想起了它
and then last night when Dr. Watson reminded me.
当时他们在等你吗?
And they were waiting for you?
是的 他们把它从我手里抢走
Yes, and they snatched it from me
当时我想把它拿上去给医生看的
as I was taking it up to him.
只有这张没有拿走
All but this.
我从那个畜生手上撕下来的
I tore it from the brute.
它在哪?
Where is it?
Miguel
Miguel.
最后一页 最后一页在哪儿?
The page, where is the last page?
他拿了 我知道 是他拿了
He has it, I know he has it.
一页纸 Carina
One page, Carina,
就算是福尔摩斯也不能...
not even Sherlock Holmes can do anything with...
把它烧了 别说了 把它烧了
Burn it, Don't talk, burn it.
脸上淌着血
Face bled,
那些无情的殴打 让他的腹中好像被火烧着一般
his stomach burned from the savage blows
可这些比起他滴血的心来说 根本算不得什么
but it was nothing to the bleeding of his heart
当他看见她那可爱的脸庞
when he saw that lovely face,
一张他愿意为之牺牲一切的脸庞
a face, which he had been prepared to sacrifice his life for.
她在笑
She smiled,
是的 苍天可鉴 她在微笑
yes by heavens, she smiled
就像是个无情的魔鬼
like the heartless fiend she was.
就在那一刻
It was at that moment
爱情死去了
that love died,
憎恨却萌生了
and hate was born.
如果不是为了你的怀抱
If it is not for your embrace my lady,
那就是为你的毁灭!  我的夫人
then it shall be for your undoing
为了我彻底的复仇
and my complete revenge.
我彻底的复仇
My complete revenge,
书里的"他"变成了"我"
The he becomes my.
作者把自己想象为男主人公
Yes, the writer imagines himself the hero.
有两本
Two copies,
一本给了Klein夫人
one to Mrs. Klein.
而这本则要出版
And this for publication.
整个伦敦都会认出
All London would recognize,
人物的原型
the wool from the lamb.
甜蜜的复仇
Sweet revenge.
再把第一句读来听听
Read me that first sentence again.
脸上淌着血
Face bled,
那些无情的殴打 让他的腹中好像被火烧着一般
his stomach burned from the savage blow.
这就是死因
The cause of death.
那老太太说肺炎是脾脏破裂引起的
Pneumonia from a ruptured spleen the old woman said.
天哪
Good heavens,
被踢破的
ruptured from a kick,
那是谋杀
that's murder.
可是我们无法证明
We could never prove it.
我要去Cricklewood
I'm leaving for Cricklewood.
Steve
Steve,
五个月前的Grover广场?
Grover's Square five months ago?
那不是我 福尔摩斯先生
That wasn't me, Mr. Holmes.
你不能把那栽在我头上
You can't put that on me.
是谁的靴子踢死了Douglas Maberley
It doesn't matter whose boot
也不要紧吗?
killed Douglas Maberley,
你们都是有罪的
you're all guilty.
哈 Susan
Ha, Susan,
Susan 在你丈夫坐牢的时候
Susan, guarding the coop
看着你的鸡舍吧
while your husband is in prison.
新来的是谁 Barney Stockdale太太?
What's the new member Mrs. Barney Stockdale?
哦 是的
Oh, yes.
小心点 福尔摩斯
Take care, Holmes.
你们从这滚出去
You get out of here.
那女人会让你坐牢的
That woman will put you behind bars
就为你昨晚做的那事
for what you did last night.
而她的雇主
And her employer,
Grosvenor广场的Klein太太
Mrs. Klein of Grosvenor Square
会看着你们全都因谋杀罪而被绞死
will see you all hanged for murder
除非你照我说的去做
unless you do what I tell you, when I tell you.
记住 Hobin的Perkins
Remember, Perkins of Hobin.
华生
Watson.
让我看看你
Let me look at you.
你看到什么了?
What do you see?
我看到了
I see,
我爱慕的女人
the woman I adore.
我准备好了
I'm ready now.
用不着 你就呆在这儿吧
No stay here,
她又不是Moriarty教授 她只不过是个女人
she's not Moriarty, she's a woman.
那只手需要补偿
That hand needs redressing.
记住 福尔摩斯
Just remember, Holmes,
女人可以比男人更致命
the female can be more deadly than the male.
估价师和拍卖人 哼
Valuer and auctioneer, my foot.
啊 夫人
Ah, Madame.
又是你 福尔摩斯
You again, Holmes.
要是你有什么要对我的新娘说的
If you have something to say to my bride,
在我把你踢出去之前赶紧说吧
speak out before I kick you out.
不 我正在等福尔摩斯先生呢 让我们单独谈谈
No, I have been expecting Mr. Holmes, leave us.
我不打算让你跟这个...
I have no intention of leaving you with this...
去吧 James
Go, James.
走啊
Go.
我很意外 你竟拖了这么久才来
I'm only surprised it took you so long.
我意外的是 你竟然以为子弹就可以恐吓我
I am surprised that you thought bullies could frighten me.
要是危险对我没有吸引力的话
No man would take up my profession
我也不会干这一行
if danger did not attract him.
您是一位绅士
You're a gentleman,
我会把您当朋友的
I will treat you as my friend.
我可无法保证会对此作出回报
I cannot promise to reciprocate.
毫无疑问
No doubt it was foolish
威胁您这么勇敢的一个人是很蠢的
to threaten such a brave man as yourself.
不 蠢的是
No, what was really foolish
像您这么一位聪明的女士
for an intelligent woman like you
竟然会让自己跟一群流氓掺和在一起
is to place yourself in the power
他们可是擅于勒索 也许还会出卖您
of a band of rascals who could blackmail, or give you away.
不不 我可不是这么头脑简单的人
No, no, I'm not so simple.
他们当中
None of them have the least idea
没人知道是谁雇佣了他们
who their employer is.
Barney Stockdale和他的妻子也不知道?
Not Barney Stockdale and his wife?
他们都是很好的猎犬
They are good hounds,
能够保守秘密
who run silent.
还愿意为你去坐牢吗?
And are prepared to go to prison for you?
他们安之若素
They take what comes,
他们拿了钱就该这样做
that's what they're paid for.
而Haines Johnson先生 噢 当然了 这不是他的真名
And Mr. Haines- Johnson oh surely that is not his name,
他拿了钱又该干什么事?
what is he paid for?
Miguel 他对我就像兄弟一样亲
Miguel, he's like a brother to me.
至于其他人嘛 他们都是干活的
As for the others they work
而在这件事中我从来没有露过面
and I do not appear in the matter.
除非我把你牵扯进去
Unless I bring you into it.
可您是位绅士 福尔摩斯先生
But you're a gentleman, Mr. Holmes,
您会尊重一位女士的隐私
you respect a woman's secret.
哼 谋杀也是隐私吗?
Huh, is murder a woman's secret?
谋杀?
Murder?
我的脸上淌着血
My face bled,
那些无情的殴打
my stomach burned,
打得他的腹中好像火烧一般
from the savage blows
可是比起我滴血的心 那不算什么
but it was nothing to the bleeding of my heart,
第245页
page 245.
还有一位目击证人 Klein夫人
And there's a witness, Mrs. Klein,
就是职业拳手Steve Dixie
the prizefighter Steve Dixie
他将指证你
who will testify against you.
这些你都告诉我未来的婆婆了吗?
And all this, you told my future mother-in-law?
我跟她说了什么并不重要
What, I told the Dowager is of no importance
因为她无法阻止你跟她儿子的婚姻
since she cannot prevent your marriage to her son.
是的 她是没有办法
No, she cannot.
而你觉得你可以吗?
And you believe that you can.
是的
Oh, yes.
你为什么要这样做呢?
Why should you wish to?
是因为我是个外国人吗?
Is it because I'm a foreigner?
你也像那些英国佬一样 是个势利鬼吗 福尔摩斯先生?
Are you an English snob, Mr. Holmes?
我来告诉你吧
Let me tell you,
我们的人几代都是
my people have been leaders in Pernambuco
Pernambuco的领袖
for generations.
夫人
Madam,
你是Andalusia 一位吉普赛人的私生子
you are the bastard child of a gypsy in Andalusia.
你这婊子养的!
Hijo de puta!
是谁告诉你的?
Who told you?
是我交换来的
It is my trade.
你必须把手稿给我
Now you must give me the manuscript.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
你想得到纸袋里的灰烬吗?
Do you wish for ashes in a paper bag?
你对我太苛刻了
You are hard to me,
看着我的眼睛
look at it with my eyes.
一生的抱负就要被你毁了
A life's ambition about to be ruined.
那是你的原罪
The original sin was yours.
是的 我认识Douglas
Yes, I know Douglas.
是的 我真的爱他
Yes, I did love him truly.
是的 我确实爱过一阵子
Yes, yes, I did for a while,
以我的方式爱着他
in my fashion.
可是他要的是婚姻
But he wanted marriage,
这是他唯一想要的
nothing less would serve him.
但这个并不符合我的计划
It did not fit with my plans.
于是你就雇了些流氓殴打他
And so you hired ruffians to beat him
直到他在你的窗下奄奄一息
until he was nearly dead under your own window,
难道这能算是淑女的所为吗?
is that the act of a lady?
没错 Barney跟那些男孩
Yes, it is true Barney and the boys
赶他走的时候也许是有些粗野
drove him away perhaps a little too roughly.
可他之后干了什么?
What did he do then,
他写了本书
he wrote a book.
对我进行恶毒地人身攻击
A vicious personal attack.
那能算是绅士的所为吗?
Is that the act of a gentleman?
你知道他的出版商并没有收到这本书?
You knew his publisher had not received it?
是的
Yes.
那它就应该还在他奶奶的房子里
So it had to be in the house of his grandmother.
只要这本书存在
As long as that book existed
我就不可能安全
there was no safety for me.
我想诚心地做这件事
I wanted to do this thing honestly.
我接受了她开出的任何价格
I offered any price she cared to ask
可她不接受
but she wouldn't take it.
难道保护自己也要受到谴责吗?
Are we to be blamed for protecting ourselves?
有一件事让我感兴趣
One thing intrigues me,
为什么像你这么一位
why a woman as lovely as you
能把男人掌握于股掌之中的美丽女士
who wields such power over men
也需要别人的保护呢?
needs the protection of anyone?
现实才不在乎我们
Nature doesn't give a damn for any of us.
我爱James
I love James,
我想要他
and I want him.
他代表着
He represents,
我想要的一切
all I've ever desired
这是我获得某种安全感的
and my one chance
一个机会
of a kind of security,
这种安全感 我称之为幸福
which I call happiness
而你却要把它从我这儿夺走
and you would take it away from me.
为什么?
Why?
因为你是男人的毁灭者
Because you are a destroyer of men.
噢 是的
Oh yes.
你毁掉了Douglas Maberley
You destroyed Douglas Maberley
还差点毁掉了我的朋友约翰 华生
and very nearly my friend John Watson
用你那种为了自身的利益...
with the ruthless disregard
...而不顾一切的漠然
for anything but your own selfish interest.
为什么在你这儿就不成功了呢?
Why have I failed with you?
我的要求只有这个...
I require only this
我要读到你跟Lomond公爵解除婚约的消息
that I read of the breaking of your engagement to the Duke of Lomond
在星期四早上之前
by Thursday morning.
要是我不答应呢?
And if I refuse?
苏格兰场
Scotland Yard,
会展开对证人的全面调查
a full investigation with witnesses.
我听你发落
I'm at your mercy,
你这个混蛋
Haz de me lopeor
悉听尊便
Do your worst.
噢 坐头等舱去环游世界
Oh, how much does it cost to go around the world
要多少钱呢?
in first class style?
我算算
Let me see, yes,
你写一张5000英镑的支票 给Maberley太太
you will send a check for 5,000 pounds to Mrs. Maberley
这是你欠她的
you owe her a little change of that.
再见 Klein夫人
Goodbye, Mrs. Klein.
我毫不怀疑 有一天我会再见到
I have no doubt I shall see you again one day,
你在一个国王的怀抱里
on the arm of a king.
于是Klein夫人 著名的美人儿
And therefore the celebrated beauty Mrs. Klein
离开前往西班牙
has departed for Spain.
她的家族几代都是
Her people have been leaders in Pernambuco
Pernambuco的领袖
for generations.
这是一篇有品位的报道
Well, it's a dignified report
不知道其他人会怎么评价它
I wonder what others would have made of it.
你让她脱罪了 福尔摩斯
You let her off the hook, Holmes.
你是说她犯了重罪吗?
Compounding a felony, you mean?
谋杀
Murder.
本来就是不可能证实的
It would have been impossible to prove.
Klein夫人已经明白了
Mrs. Klein has learned,
一个道理
that you can't play with edged tools forever
那就是
without cutting those,
"玩火者必自焚"
aging hands of hers.
岁月不饶人
Time is not on her side.
我们走吧
Shall we?
风软FRM字幕组作品 -==http://www.1000fr.com==- 欢迎加入
welcome to www.1000fr.com